Since we have our class diagram, we can move
on to the second part of the task, which is:
Next year on Saturday 16th of January
at 8 pm, I want to watch "The Ring of
the Lords" in the theatre, which is played
in the "Bluesky" room. The director of the
film is Volkert Mort and the main actor is Harry
Topper. There is a little more of the main text.
For this information here, we need to give an
object diagram that needs to conform to the class
diagram that we've just made in the first subtask.
So, starting off, we need a theatre again.
So, we don't necessarily have to name all of
these. So, we can just put these double points
here with nothing in front of this. This kind
of shows that this is an unnamed object here.
But it's of the Class theater. You can also
underline it to indicate that this is an object.
Theater in our class diagram didn't have any
attributes or methods. So, we're just going to
get rid of these placeholders here and just
leave it like this. Then we have our event
that is going on. In this case, this is a film.
Since this is a generalization going on here, we
don't need a specific Class of type Event. We just
need an object. So, an object of type Film here.
The object itself doesn't really need to have
a name. We could put the Ring of the Lords up
in here as well. But since the event itself has a
name, we can just put it as an attribute instead.
So, the name is the Ring of the Lords.
For that, we're going to need to make our
object box a little wider. The film also
has the attributes director and main actor in
our class diagram. So, we need those as well.
They are given in the text as well. The director
of that famous Volkert Mort. So we have 'director'.
The main actor is Harry Topper.
And that's our film object done. Since the film
is inheriting from the event, it inherits the
same kind of relation to the theater. So,
this is just a simple association here.
Once again, we can copy and paste this label
here. So, the theater conducts this film.
With that, we have the event that's going on
in our object diagram and its relation to the
theater. And we can move on to the date
where this is happening. Or we could move
on with the room. Either way, we're just going
to go somewhat in order here. So, the time this
is going on is Saturday 16th of January at
8 pm. So, we're going to add a date object.
Underline this as well, which has three
attributes, date, time, and price. In this case,
our date is the 16th of January. We can
just leave it like that. We don't really
know how calendar date types are defined.
But let's assume it's just writing this down.
It's happening next year on a Saturday. Saturday
doesn't really come into play here, but next year, we
can put this as 2021. Since it's 2020 currently.
Then we have the time, which is given to us as
20:00 hours. So, we're going to put it like that
as well. Once again, we don't really know how time
classes are defined. But this
is good enough in this case.
And we have the price, of course, which is
going to be eight euros, which we're just
going to put as you would normally put down
any currencies. That gives us our date class.
Now the date has a simple association with events.
So, we're just going to pull a single line here
for which we can copy this. Didn't copy all of it.
There we go. Drawio is a little fiddly sometimes. So,
this is the date of this film. So, this is our
date and film modeled in our object diagram now.
And we can move on to the seats that we're
booking. For this, we could either start
with the room because we definitely need the
room. Because there's a composition going on
here. And the theater consists of rooms where the
room consists of seats. So, we definitely need an
object of the room class as well. Or we could go
the other way around and start with the booking.
And just put the booking class, which in
our case, since this is an object diagram,
doesn't get any method. So, this is just going
to be a booking object here with no attributes
connected to our date through the simple
association as we did in our class diagram.
We can copy this label. So, this is our booking
for that date. And the booking consists of
multiple seats. Since we are booking two seats,
we need to model two seat objects as well. So,
we can put a name in here or just
leave it empty again. We can put a seat
and underline it. And seats have numbers. So, put
seat number one for the attributes. And another
one, which is going to be seat number two, which
is going to be our two booked seats. Both of those are
connected to booking via an aggregation,
as we did in our class diagram.
Some of these pre-made objects aren't that great.
Get rid of this relation, and we get rid of these
multiplicities. Since we are in an object
diagram, we don't really want or need these.
And we are going to replace this one to get
another one. Connecting our booking to this
second seat. There we go. We can get rid of
these arrowheads if we want to. But since
we're using them here in the class diagram
as well, we can just leave it like that too.
I just noticed you couldn't actually see the
other seat. I'm just going to move over a bit.
Our seats are now sort of disconnected here. We
have these compositions here from theater to room
and room to seat. So, we definitely need the room
object as well. So, let's make that. We could name
this room one if we wanted to, just to have one
object with the actual name. Rooms have names.
And the name is given in our task as well. This
is the "Bluesky" room. So, the name is "Bluesky."
No further attributes. And our room is
connected through compositions to the
seats and to theaters. So, we grab those as well.
Just copy and paste it from up here. Connecting
the theater to the room. Moving this multiplicity.
And connecting each seat to the room. This is
very fiddly.
I'm not sure what's doing that. But this sort
of works. There we go. If you're using drawio,
you need to be careful to hit these little
anchor points that show up sometimes. So,
this is our room connected to the seats now and
the room connected to the theater. And with that,
we have almost everything modeled. We're just
missing this association between date and room
here. So, you can pull a normal line to the room.
And once again, copy this label here, which tells
us, that on this date there is something
happening in that room.
And looking at our task description again. See
if we got everything. We got the date with all
information given here. We've got the event that's
going on. We have a room named "Bluesky." We have
our two seats. And we have
our booking. So, that's our
object diagram dealt with as
well. And this completes the task.